<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
         xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
   <rdf:Description>
      <dc:title>An Anglo-American alliance: A Serio-Comic Romance and Forecast of the Future</dc:title>
      <dc:creator>Gregory Casparian (1856–1947)</dc:creator>
      <dc:publisher>Project Gutenberg, Urbana, Illinois, USA., 2016-08-28</dc:publisher>
      <dc:date>2016-08-28</dc:date>
      <dc:rights>This eBook is for the use of anyone anywhere at no cost and with almost no restrictions whatsoever. You may copy it, give it away or re-use it under the terms of the Project Gutenberg License included with this eBook or online at www.gutenberg.org.
This eBook is produced by the Online Distributed Proofreading Team at www.pgdp.net.
Scans of this book are available from The Internet Archive (copy 1, 2).
</dc:rights>
      <dc:subject>Lesbians -- Fiction</dc:subject>
      <dc:subject>Lesbians</dc:subject>
      <dc:description>This curious self-published book by the Turkish-Armenian author Gregory Casparian was published in 1906, but the events are set in 1960, and the book introduces a lot of scientific innovations and an alternative history. In the narrative, Aurora Cunningham, daughter of Great Britain’s Secretary of Foreign Affairs, and Margaret MacDonald, daughter of an American senator, meet and fall in love. However, because of social prejudice they have to suppress their feelings. Ultimately, a doctor helps her to transform into a man, Spencer Hamilton, and the couple can marry.

This is one of the first novels touching lesbian and transgender issues; something that appears still to be a hot-topic in some reactionary circles in the US today. For its time, it was quite out of the ordinary. On the flip side, however, it also includes a number of racial slurs that clearly place it back into its era. There seems to be something in this book to offend everyone.</dc:description>
      <dc:identifier>pg:52913</dc:identifier>
   </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>